
    
        
            
                Ephrem — ܐܦܪܝܡ
                
                Syriaca.org: The Syriac Reference Portal
                The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation
                The National Endowment for the Humanities
                The International Balzan Prize Foundation
                David A. Michelson
                Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                David A. Michelson
                Nathan P. Gibson
                Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                David A. Michelson
                Nathan P. Gibson
                James E. Walters
                Thomas A. Carlson
                Kristian Heal
                André Binggeli
                Françoise Briquel-Chatonnet
                Muriel Debié
                Alain Desreumaux
                Emilie Villey
                Youssef Dergham
                Margherita Farina
                Simone I. M. Pratelli
                Flavia Ruani
                Eleonora Serra
                
                    These names were received as a dataset from E-Ktobe : manuscrits syriaques 
                            (http://syriac.msscatalog.org/). 
                            Née sur l’initiative d'André Binggeli (IRHT-CNRS), Françoise Briquel-Chatonnet (Orient et Méditerranée-CNRS), 
                            Muriel Debié (EPHE) et Alain Desreumaux (Orient et Méditerranée-CNRS) dans le cadre du programme 
                            SYRAB de l'ANR (Agence Nationale de la Recherche), la base e-ktobe est actuellement placée sous la responsabilité 
                            scientifique d’André Binggeli et Emilie Villey (Orient et Méditerranée-CNRS).                            
                            Liste des collaborateurs contribuant ou ayant contribué à l’alimentation de la base : 
                            Youssef Dergham (Bibliothèque du patriarcat syro-catholique de Charfet), Margherita Farina (CNRS, Paris), 
                            Simone I. M. Pratelli (U. de Constance), Flavia Ruani (U. de Gand) et Eleonora Serra (U. de Pise).
                    E-Ktobe : manuscrits syriaques
                
                
                    Data from Macuch, Abuna, De Urbina, Duval, Assemani (vols. 1-2), Chabot, Wright, and Brock collected, verified, reconciled, and entered by
                    Kristian Heal
                
                
                    German data entry by
                    Samer Khader
                
                
                    Editing, proofreading, data entry and revision by
                    Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                
                
                    Editing, document design, data architecture, encoding, proofreading, data entry by
                    David A. Michelson
                
                
                    Proofreading of GEDSH abstracts, addition of confessions and alternate names from GEDSH, matching with viaf.org records, data entry, data transformation, data merging, conversion to XML by
                    Nathan P. Gibson
                
                
                    GEDSH and Barsoum English name entry, matching with viaf.org records by
                    James E. Walters
                
                
                    Editing, Syriac name entry, disambiguation research, conversion to XML by
                    Thomas A. Carlson
                
                
                    Editing, Syriac data conversion, data entry, and reconciling by
                    Adam P. Kane
                
                
                    Editing and Syriac data proofreading by
                    Aram Bar Schabo
                
                
                    Syriac name entry by
                    Robert Aydin
                
                
                    Normalization of GEDSH dates and entry matching with viaf.org records by
                    Alex Vawter
                
                
                    Editorial oversight for GEDSH and Barsoum English text entry, and proofreading by
                    Christopher Johnson
                
                
                    GEDSH and Barsoum English text entry and proofreading by
                    the Syriac Research Group, University of Alabama
                
                
                    Entries adapted from the work of
                    Jean Maurice Fiey
                
                
                    Entries adapted from the work of
                    Ugo Zanetti
                
                
                    Entries adapted from the work of
                    Claude Detienne
                
            
            
                
            
            
                Syriaca.org: The Syriac Reference Portal
                http://syriaca.org/person/13/tei
                
                    
                        Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.
                        This entry incorporates copyrighted material from the following work(s):
                                    
                                
                                    
                                
                                
                                    
                                
                            
                            used under a Creative Commons Attribution license 
                            
                        
                    
                
                2016-08-17-04:00
            
            
                The Syriac Biographical Dictionary
                David A. Michelson
                Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                Nathan P. Gibson
                Daniel L. Schwartz
                
                    Edited by
                    David A. Michelson
                
                
                    Edited by
                    Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                
                
                    Edited by
                    Nathan P.  Gibson
                
                
                    Edited by
                    Daniel L. Schwartz
                
                http://syriaca.org/persons
                
                    Qadishe: A Guide to the Syriac Saints
                    http://syriaca.org/q
                
                
                    A Guide to Syriac Authors
                    http://syriaca.org/authors
                
            
            
                Gateway to the Syriac Saints
                Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                David A.
                Michelson
                
                    Edited by
                    Jeanne-Nicole Mellon Saint-Laurent
                
                
                    Edited by
                    David A.
                    Michelson
                
                http://syriaca.org/saints
                
                    Qadishe: A Guide to the Syriac Saints
                    http://syriaca.org/q
                
            
            
                Born digital.
            
        
        
            
                This record created following the Syriaca.org guidelines. 
                        Documentation available at: http://syriaca.org/documentation.
                
                    Approximate dates described in terms of centuries or partial centuries
                            have been interpreted as documented in 
                            Syriaca.org Dates.
                
            
            
                
                    
                        The name used by Syriaca.org for document titles, citation, and disambiguation. 
                                These names have been created according to the Syriac.org guidelines for headwords: 
                                http://syriaca.org/documentation/headwords.html.
                    
                    
                        An anglicized version of a name, included to facilitate searching.
                    
                
                
                    
                        A person who is relevant to the Guide to Syriac Authors
                    
                    
                        A person who is relevant to the Bibliotheca Hagiographica Syriaca.
                    
                
            
        
        
            
                Unvocalized Syriac of any variety or period
                Vocalized West Syriac
                Vocalized East Syriac
                English
                Names or terms Romanized into English according to the standards 
                        adopted by the Gorgias Encyclopedic Dictionary of the Syriac Heritage
                Arabic
                French
                German
                Latin
            
        
        
            Merged in data from [duplicate record with same URI].
            CREATED: person [duplicate record with same URI]
            Moved relation/@name to relation/@ref
            Moved relation/@name to relation/@ref
            Add relations and attestations for saints-overlap.
            Update persName texts nodes from new headwords.
            Merged in Baumstark data
            Add bibl ptr elements.
            Split names in authors into forename and surname.
            Manual edit of merged data including standardizing header and abstracts.
            Merged in data from [duplicate record with same URI].
            CHANGED: Corrected swapped source attributes for data from Fiey and Zanetti [duplicate record with same URI]
            Added French names from BHSE.
            CREATED: person [duplicate record with same URI]
            ADDED: Renumbered bibl xml:id attributes and source references to be sequential.
            ADDED: Abstracts, citation, additional names and confessions from GEDSH.
            ADDED: syriaca-computed-end for elements with date attributes
             CREATED: person 
        
    
    
        
            
                
                    
                        Ephrem
                    
                    
                        Ephrem
                    
                    
                        St.
                        Ephraim
                        the Syrian
                    
                    
                        مار
                        افرام
                        الملفان
                        السرياني
                    
                    
                        ܡܪܝ
                        ܐܦܪܝܡ
                    
                    
                        ܡܳܪܝ
                        ܐܰܦܪܶܝܡ
                    
                    
                        ܐܦܪܝܡ
                    
                    
                        ܐܲܦܪܹܝܡ
                    
                    
                        Ephraim
                    
                    
                        Éphrem
                    
                    
                        Ephrem
                    
                    Ephrem of Edessa
                    Saint Ephrem
                    ʾAfrēm
                    Éphrem d’Édesse
                    SAINT ÉPHREM
                    
                        Ap(h)rem
                    
                    Éphrem le Syrien
                    Éphrem de Nisibe
                    http://syriaca.org/person/13
                    http://viaf.org/viaf/sourceID/SRP|person_13
                    http://viaf.org/viaf/100177778
                    http://worldcat.org/identities/lccn-n50-82928
                    http://worldcat.org/identities/np-ephrem$syrus saint$303 373
                    http://worldcat.org/identities/np-ephraem$syrus$ca 306 ca 373
                    http://www.csc.org.il/db/browse.aspx?db=SB&sL=E&sK=Ephraim&sT=keywords
                    http://www.csc.org.il/db/browse.aspx?db=SB&sL=E&sK=Ephrem&sT=keywords
                    147
                    
                        Deacon, poet, and theologian.
                    
                    male
                    373
                    In hagiography: Ephrem is commemorated as a doctor of the church and theologian. Ephrem's ecclesiastical career was based mainly in Nisibis and Edessa. He was the author of hymns, homilies, and prose. His fourth-century writings are remembered as a "golden age" of Syriac literature. His vita as recounted in hagiography differs greatly from historical accounts. One vita transforms him into a Byzantine monk, which is nevertheless a tribute to his importance in both the Syriac and Byzantine Greek churches.
                    Saint Ephrem is celebrated by the Syrians on January 28.
                    The bibliography on Ephrem is immense.
                    
                        St.
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (Variation) (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem (Testament) (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            Ephrem is commemorated in Ephrem of Edessa (text) — .
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                S. P.
                                Brock
                            
                        
                        Ephrem
                        The Gorgias Encyclopedic Dictionary of the Syriac Heritage
                        
                        145-147
                    
                    
                        The Scattered Pearls: A History of Syriac Literature and Sciences
                        
                        9
                        229
                    
                    
                        كتاب اللؤلؤ المنثور في تاريخ العلوم والأداب السريانية
                        
                        196
                    
                    
                        ܒܪ̈ܘܠܐ ܒܕܝܪ̈ܐ ܕܥܠ ܡܪܕܘܬ ܝܘܠܦܢ̈ܐ ܣܘܪ̈ܝܝܐ ܗܕܝܪ̈ܐ
                        
                        218
                    
                    
                        ܟܬ̣ܵܒ̣ܵܐ ܕܡܸܬ̣ܩܪܸܐ ܡܪܓܢܝܬ̣ܐ ܕܥܲܠ ܫܪܵܪܵܐ ܕܲܟ̣ܪܸܣܛܝܵܢܘܼܬ̣ܵܐ
                        
                        69
                    
                    
                        Bibliotheca Orientalis Clementino-Vaticana
                        
                        III:61
                    
                    
                        A Comprehensive Bibliography on Syriac Christianity
                        
                        Ephraim
                        Ephrem
                    
                    
                        Bibliotheca Hagiographica Syriaca
                        
                        176
                        345
                        346
                        347
                        348
                        350
                        351
                        352
                        353
                        354
                        355
                        356
                        357
                        358
                        359
                        360
                        361
                        362
                        363
                        364
                        365
                        366
                        367
                        368
                        369
                        370
                        371
                        372
                        373
                        374
                        375
                        376
                        377
                        378
                        379
                        380
                        381
                        382
                        383
                        384
                        385
                        386
                        387
                        388
                        389
                        390
                        391
                        392
                        393
                        394
                        395
                        396
                        398
                        399
                        400
                        401
                        402
                        403
                        728
                        729
                        794
                        795
                        796
                        797
                        798
                        799
                        800
                        801
                        802
                        803
                        804
                        805
                        806
                        807
                        808
                        809
                        810
                        811
                        812
                        813
                        815
                        816
                        817
                        818
                        819
                        820
                        821
                        822
                        823
                        824
                        825
                        826
                        827
                        828
                        829
                        830
                        831
                        832
                        833
                        834
                        908
                        996
                        999
                        1063
                        1140
                        1141
                        1255
                        1317
                        1318
                        1319
                        1320
                        1340
                        1466
                        1517
                        1539
                        1742
                        1743
                        1759
                        1760
                        1773
                        1774
                        1786
                        1813
                        1825
                        1826
                        1827
                        1828
                        1829
                        1830
                        1945
                        1985
                        1988
                        1996
                        95
                        96
                        788
                        789
                        1158
                        1892
                        1593
                        244
                    
                    
                        Saints Syriaques
                        SAINT ÉPHREM
                        
                        147
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                K.
                                den Biesen
                            
                        
                        Bibliography of Ephrem the Syrian
                        
                        (Giove in Umbria, 2002)
                    
                    
                        "Saint Ephrem d'apres sa biographie et ses ceuvres"
                        
                            
                                Dom B.
                                Outier
                            
                        
                        Parole d'Orient
                        
                        4 (1973), 12-53
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                J.
                                Amar
                            
                        
                        "Byzantine Ascetic Monachism and Greek
               Bias in the Vita Tradition of Ephrem the Syrian"
                        
                        OCP 58 (1992), 123-58
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                J.M.
                                Fiey
                            
                        
                        Nisibe
                        
                        123-35
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                S.P.
                                Brock
                            
                        
                        The Luminous Eye : the Spiritual World Vision of St Ephrem the
               Syrian.
                        
                        Kalamazoo, 1992
                    
                    
                        
                            
                                J.-M.
                                Sauget
                            
                        
                        BS
                        
                        IV,
               944-49
                    
                    
                        Baumstark, Geschichte der syrischen Literatur mit Ausschluß der christlich-palästinensischen Texte
                        
                        31-52
                    
                    
                        Ortiz de Urbina, Patrologia Syriaca
                        
                        18
                    
                    
                        Duval, La littérature syriaque
                        
                        329-335
                    
                    
                        De scriptoribus Syris orthodoxis
                        Bibliotheca orientalis Clementino-Vaticana
                        
                        24-164
                    
                    
                        Chabot, Littérature syriaque
                        
                        25-30
                    
                    
                        Wright, A Short History of Syriac Literature
                        
                        33-37
                    
                    
                        Brock, A brief outline of Syriac literature
                        
                        16-22
                    
                    
                        E-ktobe : manuscrits syriaques
                        Catalogue de manuscrits
                        
                    
                
                
                    
                        This author has a literary connection to places.
                    
                    
                        This author has an unspecified connection to places.
                    
                
            
        
    
